Guide to the Urie Bronfenbrenner papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
Bronfenbrenner, Urie papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
- Series III. Published Works
  - White House Conference: Children and Parents, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Liberated Women: Interview, 1976-06-07 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - The Experimental Ecology of Education, 1976-10 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Research on the Effects of Day Care on Child Development, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - The Experimental Ecology of Education, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - The Next Generation of Americans: An International Perspective, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Ecology of Human Development, 1974-1977 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - To Nurture Children, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Black Families and the Socialization of Black Children, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Sage Chapel Convocation, 1977-12-04 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Socialization Practices of Parents, Teachers and Peers in Israel: Children of Immigrants from Eastern and Western Nations, 1976-08 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Strengthening Families through Flexible Work Schedules: Correspondence, 1977-04-26 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - The Next Generation, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Research on Parent-Child Relations and Social Policy, 1977-04 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - "Toward and Experimental Ecology of Human Development", 1977-07 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - "Who Needs Parent Education?" (Draft), 1977-09-14 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Parent Education: It's Not Just for Parents, 1978-10 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Child rearing, Parenthood and the World of Work, 1978-03 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Family Stresses and Supports (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Family Matters: Common Concern of Business and Parents, 1978-08-15 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Alternatives to a Deficit Model for American Families and Children, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Children in America: The Roots of Alienation, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - "Okologishe Sozialisationasforschung", 1978 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - School Effectiveness in Ecological Perspective (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - American Research on the Development of Children in their Environment, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - The Ecology of Human Development: Reviews, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Social Policy Implications of "The Comparative Ecology of Human Development", 1979-04 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Family and the Next Generations of Americans, 1979-04-11 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Testimony: White House Conference On Families, 1979-11-16 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Head Start Reminiscences, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Book Review: Class in a Classless Societyh, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - "Beyond the Deficit Model in Child and Family Policy", 1979 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Cornell Child Care Coalition, 1980-1 (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Head Start in the 1980s, 1980-09 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Review of Jensen's "Bias in Mental Testing", 1980-04 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Ithaca Journal Letter to the Editor, 1980-06-04 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Toward Improving Human Ecology: Interview, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 42)
    Published in the Spring
  - Ecology of Childhood, 1980-09 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - U.S. Dept of Health, Education, and Welfare: Head Start, 1980-03-13 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Menschliche Umwelt fur menschliche Entwicklung (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - The Ecology of Human Development: German (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Ansfield Wolf Award, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - L'Ecologie Experimentale de l'Education, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - The New American Dilemma: Work versus Family, 1981-02 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - The Mismeasure of Man: Review and Correspondence (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Hidden Revolution: Correspondence, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - "Soziale Umweltzerstorung", 1981-05-1981-06 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - "Uber Urie Bronfenbrenner" by Herwig Blankertz and Hellmut Becker, 1981-05-1981-06 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - "New Images of Children, Families and America", 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    Published in the of Fall 1981 and the Winter of 1982
  - Work and Family Through Time and Space: Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Travel Journal, 1982-01-1982-06 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Continuity of Values in a Changing World, 1982-08-20 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - Wiley Review of Alison Clarke-Stewart's Chapter, 1982-08 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Commentary on "Trio of Trials", 1982 (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - The Evolution of Environmental Models in Developmental Research, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Science and Human Development: The Hidden Revolution, 1983-07-22 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Committee on Soviet Studies at Cornell (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - The Importance of Third Parties: Some Longer-Range Effects, 1984-01-12 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Towards at Critical Social History of Developmental Psychology (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - New Worlds for Families, 1984-04-30 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Japanese Research and Reality in the Field of Child Development, 1983-1984 (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - Families and Education in the U.S. and Other Countries, 1984-09 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Comments on: Mother Care/Other Care by Sandra Scarr, 1984-01-04 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Chapter 3. Exploring Human Development (Draft), 1984 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - The Future of Childhood, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Summary of Beginnings: The Social and Affective Development of Black Children, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Organism-Environment Interaction from an Ecological Perspective, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - Infancia Letter (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - Midtveis I den menneskelige utviklings økologi, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - "'Don't Forget to Take the Cupcakes out of the Oven': Prospective Memory, Strategic Time-Monitoring, and Context" with Stephen J. Ceci, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - "Freedom and Discipline Across the Decades", 1985 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - HDFS/PSYCH 488. Development in Context. Lecture 19. Parenthood and Adult Development (Part II), 1985-11-08 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - "The Ecology of Human Development in Mid-Passage", 1985 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - "The Three Worlds of Childhood", 1985-05 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Foreword to Contributions to a History of Developmental Psychology, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Changing Families and Child Rearing: What Can Parents Do?, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 75)
  - Alienation and the Four Worlds of Childhood, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Recent Advances in Research on the Ecology of Human Development, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - Ecology of the Family as a Context for Human Development: Research Perspectives, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 73)
  - A Generation in Jeopardy: America's Hidden Family Policy, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 74)
  - The War on Poverty: Won or Lost? America's Children in Poverty: 1959-1985, Summer 1986 (Box 17, Folder 76)
  - Foreword: When Teenagers Work, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 77)
  - Toward a Critical Social History of Developmental Psychology: A Propaedeutic Discussion, 1986-11 (Box 17, Folder 78)
  - Technical University Honorary Degree, 1986-07-4 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - "Acceptace Speech for Honorary Degree from Technische Universitat Berlin", 1986 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - "Dix annees de recherece sure l'ecologie du developpment humain", 1986 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - "Ecology of the Family as a Context for Human Development: Research Perspectives", 1986 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Foreword Family Support: The Quiet Revolution, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 79)
  - "Chapter 2 The Changing Family in a Changing World" (Draft), 1987-01-26 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - "The Ecology of Human Development", 1987 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Advisor's Foreword, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - "La Cambiante ecologia de la infancia. Implicaciones en el terreno de la ciecia y de la accion" (The changing ecology of childhood: Implications for Science and Action), 1987 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - Strengthening Family Systems, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 80)
  - Prospective Remembering, Temporal Calibration, and Context, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 81)
  - Foreword: Violence, Youth, and a Way Out, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 82)
  - Paradoxes of Prenatal Risk, Spring 1988 (Box 17, Folder 83)
  - Interacting systems in human development, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 84)
  - Alternatives to a Deficit Model for American Families and Children: Critical Thinking, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 85)
  - World of Children Awards, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - HDFS/PSYCH 488. Development in Context. "The Changing Family in a Changing World", 1988-01-26 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Foreword to Ecological Research with Children and Families, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - Youthful Designs for Research on Aging, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 86)
  - "Memory in Context: The Case of Prospective Remembering" with S.J. Ceci and J.G. Baker, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - The Interplay of Organism and Environment in Early Development: The Case of Low Birth Weight, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 87)
  - Ecological Models for Youth Research Real and Imagined, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 88)
  - Who Cares for Children?, 1989-12 (Box 17, Folder 89)
  - The Case for the Family (Box 17, Folder 90)
  - The Dangers of No Daycare, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 91)
  - Investing in Our Children, 1989-10-1989-11 (Box 17, Folder 92)
  - Ecological Systems Theory, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 93)
  - The Developing Ecology of Human Development: Paradigm Lost of Paradigm Regained, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 94)
  - "Early Childhood Education Programs Needs and Dangers" (Testimony at a Hearing of the subcommittee on Education and Health of the Joint Economic Committee of the House and Senate), 1989-05-01 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Foreword to Extending Families: The Social Networks of Parents and their Children, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - "Kognitiivisen Kehitykesen ekologia: Tutkimusmalleja ja pakenevia tuloksia" (The Ecology of Cognitive Development: Research models and fugitive findings), 1989 (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - "Who Cares for Children?" Bilingual version, Address, 1989 and Edited Essay, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - "The Ecology of Developmental Processes Orientation and Outline", 1980-1989 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - "Generationenbeziehungen in der Okologie menschlicher Entwicklung", 1990-1999 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - Forword to the Japanese edition of Ecology of Human Development, 1990-1999 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - "America's Children and Families", 1990-1999 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - Addresses given by Bronfenbrenner, 1990-1999 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - "Youth and Nationhood: An International Challenge" (bilingual), 1990-1999 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - "Recent Publications", 1990-1999 (Box 18, Folder 63)
  - Ökologische Sozialisationsforschung, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 95)
  - Discovering What Families Do, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 96)
  - Ökologische Modelle in der Jugendforschung: Anspruch and Wirklichkeit, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 97)
  - Cities are for Families, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 98)
  - Distancing Theory from a Distance, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 99)
  - "Las Cuidades son para las familas" I Congres Internacional de Ciutats Educadores, Barcelona, 1990-11-26-1990-11-30 (Box 25, Folder 53)
  - Articles, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 100)
  - William Raspberry Article, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 101)
  - What do Families Do?, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 102)
  - Tribute to Urie Bronfenbrenner - Congressional Record, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 103)
  - "Constructive Processes: Their Power and Some Limitations", 1991-05-13 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - "'The American Parent': NCFT 1991 Conference Proceedings" (Box 25, Folder 55)
  - "Newborns, Mothers, and Social Order" (Draft), 1991-12-02 (Box 25, Folder 56)
  - "On the Demise of Everyday Memory" with Stephen J. Ceci, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - "The Nurture of Nature", 1991 (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - Foreword: The Twelve Who Survive, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Gibt es Universalien in der Kindererziehung?, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Forum Interview, Spring 1992 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Hand to Hand: Association of Youth Museums, Summer 1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Espacio Lewiniano y Contenido, 1992-10 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Evolution de la famille dans un monde en mutation, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Drillien's Pioneering Study, 1992-01-23 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Child Care in the Anglo-Saxon Mode, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Nature-Nurture Reconceptualized, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - The Process-Person-Context Model in Developmental Research, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - "Prologo de Urie Bronfenbrenner Traduccion de Sylvia Schmelkes,", 1992 (Box 25, Folder 58)
  - "Espacio Lewiniano y Contenido Ecologico,", 1992-10 (Box 25, Folder 59)
  - Advisor's Foreword to Child Development: Its Nature and Course, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - "Developmental Pathways to and from the Urban Underclass: Commentary from and Ecological Perspective", 1992-06 (Box 25, Folder 61)
  - Ecological Models of Human Development, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Developmental Pathways to and from the Urban Underclass, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - The Ecology of Cognitive Development: Research Models and Fugitive Findings, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Kognitiivisen kenityksen ekologia, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - The Ecology of Cognitive Development, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - The Ecology of Human Development, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Heredity, Environment, and the Question "How?", 1993 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Distancing Theory From a Distance, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Foreword to Parenting An Ecological Perspective, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Living through Societal Chaos, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - No Other University (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Environments in Developmental Perspective, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - A New Head Start for Head Start, 1993-11-04-07 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - America's Children and Families in International Perspective, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Cognition In and Out of Context: a Tale of Two Paradigms, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Psychometric and Everyday Intelligence, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Ecological Models of Human Development, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - A Review of "Developing Minds", 1994 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Foreword: Child Care and Culture Lesson from Africa, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - The Westernization of Asian Cultures, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Towards a more developmental behavioral genetics, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Nature-Nurture Reconceptualized in Developmental Perspective, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Community Talk, 1994-10-05 (Box 25, Folder 62)
  - Book Review of Jobs and Psychological Development: A New Sociological Perspective, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - "10: Cognition In and Out of Context: A Tale of Two Paradigms", 1994 (Box 25, Folder 64)
  - "11: Psychometric and Everyday Intelligence: Synonyms, Antonyms, and Anonyms" with Stephen J. Ceci and Jacqueline G. Baker-Sennett, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 64)
  - "America's Children and Families An International Perspective" with Peter R. Neville, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - "Human Ecology: Concepts and Perspectives" (Keynote Speech, International Symposium), 1994-10-27-28 (Box 25, Folder 66)
  - Chapters in "Examining lives in context", 1995 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Toward a Research Design for Early Head Start (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - "The Bell Curve", 1995 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Comments on "The Bell Curve" from Tara (Box 25, Folder 67)
  - A Less Perfect Union (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - The New American University, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - "The Bioecological Model from a Life Course Perspective: Reflections of a Participant Observer", 1995 (Box 25, Folder 68)
  - "Developmental Ecology Through Space and Time: A Future Perspective", 1995 (Box 25, Folder 68)
  - Prospect for the Social Sciences in the Land-Grant University, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Japanese Childhood, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - A World for Baby XXI, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Foreword: Developmental Science and Holistic Approach, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - The Apocalypse is Now, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Centennial of Lev Semyonovich Vygotsky, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - "The Process-Person-Context Model in Developmental Research Principles, Applications, and Implications", 1996 (Box 25, Folder 69)
  - "Toward a Comprehensive Theoretical Framework for Disablility Research - Bronfenbrenner Revisited", 1996 (Box 25, Folder 70)
  - "The State of Americans This Generation and the Next," (Draft), 1996 (Box 25, Folder 71)
  - Response to Reviews of 'The State of Americans', 1996 (Box 25, Folder 72)
  - Beyond the Numbers, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - Museums and Child Developments, 1997-02-03 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - Systems vs. Associations, 1997-03-1997-04 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  - The Ecology of Developmental Processes, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 60)
  - "On Making Human Beings Human, Some Facts and Speculations", 1997 (Box 25, Folder 73)
  - "The Apocalypse is Now" (Talk given at St.Pauls UMC) Published in the Herald Examiner, 1997-03 (Box 25, Folder 74)
  - Foreword to "Children, Cities, and Psychological Theories", 1998 (Box 18, Folder 59)
  - "Alternatives to a Deficit Model for American Families and Children", 1998 (Box 25, Folder 75)
  - "Could the Answer Be Talent?" with Stephen J. Ceci, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 76)
  - "The Ecology of Developmental Processes" with Pamela Morris, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 77)
  - Foreword to Children of the Great Depression, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 78)
  - Growing Chaos in the Lives of Children, Youth, and Families, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 61)
  - "Environments in Developmental Perspective: Theoretical and Operational Models", 1999 (Box 25, Folder 79)
  - "Growing Chaos in the Lives of Children, Youth and Families: How Can We Turn it Around?" (Article and Presentation), 1999 (Box 25, Folder 80)
  - "Elements of the Microsystem" (Draft), 1999-09-01 (Box 25, Folder 81)
  - Developmental Science in the 21st Century, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Penn State Honorary Degree and Commencement, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - Human Ecology: The Legacy of Learning, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 65)
  - "The Bioecological Theory of Human Development" for encyclopedia article with several drafts and revisions, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 82)
  - The Bioecological Theory of Human Development, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - Spanish Works (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Various Textbook Excerpts on the Ecological Systems Theory (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - "A Checklist for the Ecological Models of Human Development" (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "What comes After the 'End'? Children in the 21st Century" (Draft) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "Appendix A: An Ecological Paradigm for Research and Child Care" (Draft) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "The Ecology of Violence A Developmental Life-Course Perspective" Presentation (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Ecological Systems Theory (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - "Intergenerational Relationships and Cross-Generational Development: An Ecological Perspective" (Draft) (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - "Japanese Childhood as a Foundation for Learning Lessons for Reality and Research" (Published in German) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - "The Graphic Analysis of Moderating Effects" and "What is an Indirect Effect?" (Drafts and Notes) (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Definitions of Theory Terms and Hand Written Notes (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Indroduction, Acknowledgements, and Discussion for a Bronfenbrenner Book (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Awards (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Who's Who (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Speech made on the State of Americans (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Testimonies to Congress (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Radio and News Stories A (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Radio and News Stories B (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Reviews (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Human Development in Cultural and Historical Contexts, Editor, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 83)
  - Influences in Human Development, Editor (Box 25, Folder 83)
  - Child Development Its Nature and Course, Advisory Editor and Foreword (Box 25, Folder 83)
  - Comments on Book Chapters, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 84)
  - Comments on Ch.2 Developmental Science: Principles and Illustrations by Magnusson and Carins (Box 25, Folder 85)
  - Comments on "Research on Head Start and its Families" (Box 25, Folder 86)
  - Comments on "Family Socialization and Children's Behavior and Personality Development in China", 1988 (Box 25, Folder 87)
  - Comments for Behavioral and Brain Sciences on Plomin & Bergeman, and Review, 1990-1991 (Box 25, Folder 88)
  - Bibliographies of various dates (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Papers written by Urie, 1930s-1940s (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Paper written as undergrad "Development and Principles", 1936 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Paper "Haydn Versus Hindemith - A Digression on a Theme" (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Title unknown (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Draft chapters on newborns, 1980-1989 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - "Ecological Systems Theory", 1989 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - "On Making Human Beings Human", 1980-1989 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Annotated publications of various dates (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Annotated publications, 1990-1999 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Professor Urie Bronfenbrenner wird Ehrendoktor der Technischen Universitat Berlin, 1986-07 (Box 33)
  - "Bioecologia do Desenvolvimento Humano", 2005 (Box 33)
  - ZSE-Journal for Sociology of Education and Socialization - articles in German about Urie, 2006 (Box 33)
  - "The Ecology of Human Development: Experiments by Nature and Design (in Japanese), 2010 (Box 33)
  - Articles by Urie - various dates (Box 31, Folder 1-5)
- Series IV. Correspondence Files
  - Unfiled Correspondence, 1988-1997 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - Aber, Larry, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Bronfenbrenner, Kate, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Burton, Linda, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Ceci, Steve, 1998-2000 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Clausen, John, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Cochran, Mon, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Elder, Glen, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Elyse (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Evans, Gary, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Fischer, Kurt, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Freiberg, Karen, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Gandini, Lella, 1985-1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Gardner, Howard, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Gerson, Menachem, 1969-1974 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Gluck, David, 1988-1999 (Box 19, Folder 119)
  - Goldschmidt, Von Dietrich, 1986-1991 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Goodman, Ellen, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Gordeeva, Tamara, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Goodnow, Jacqueline, 1981-1995 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Goslin, David, 1971-1975 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Gorlitz, Dietmar, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Guidubaldi, John, 1984-1988 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Gylfadottir, Unnur, 1996-1997 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Hammond, Kenneth R., 1978 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Harris, Irving, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Von Hentig, Hartmut, 1967-1992 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Hetherington, Maud, 1981-1983 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Hobbs, Nick, 1979-1982 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Hoffman, Lois, 1981-1983 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Horn, Wade F. (Fatherhood Initiative), 1994 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Ipsa, Jean, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Isogai, Yoshiro, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Jacobson, Kristen, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - Jensen, Arthur, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Johnson, Sidney, 1975-1982 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Kagan, Jerome, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Kahn, Alfred J., 1972-1975 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Kav-Venaki, Sophia, 1972-1976 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Kaufmann, Franz X., 1995 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Keating, Dan, 1992-1995 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Kessen, Bill, 1975-1986 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Keyes, Susan, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Kinderman, Thomas, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - Klaus, Sarah, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Klineberg, Otto, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Knitzer, Jane (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Koel, Amy, 1976-1987 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Kohn, Melvin L., 1974-1993 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Kojima, Hideo, 1981-1993 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Komiosi, Sandor, 1967-1992 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Kon, I.S., 1975-1992 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Kondo, Chie, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Koshland, Daniel, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - Lamb, Michael, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 40)